Hongjia Ren

0469331139 hongjia.ren.work@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/hongjia-ren-/ Based in Sydney

PROFILE

Experienced Python Developer specializing in software, application, and database development. Previously demostrating ability to improve system performance, reporting, and reliability throughout the SDLC. Proficient in collaborating with stakeholders, conducting performance tests, and delivering efficient solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Python, PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS
- Framework: Vue.js, Express.js, Django, Flask, Spring Boot, jQuery, React
- Database Cloud Services: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, GraphQL,AWS
- Tools: Git, RESTful API, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Agile/Scrum, JIRA

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Support Engineer JAGOPS PTY LTD, Randwick, Sydney

November 2023 - Now

- Provided responsive user support: Delivering prompt technical assistance, swiftly resolving hardware and software issues.
- Collaborated with IT team to seamlessly resolve complex issues, optimizing efficiency by ~50% through strategic management with Google Docs.

Python Engineer

May 2022 - October 2022

Sichuan Juxingyiju Logistics PTY LTD, China

- **Optimized Application Speed**: Led development of an internal GIS application, emphasizing map visualization, geographic analysis, and location intelligence.
- **Improved Efficiency:** Designed and developed an internal project management platform with Vue.js, **achieving a 40%** boost in application speed.
- Continuous Delivery Implementation: Implemented a continuous delivery process, resulting in a 30% increase in deployment frequency.
- **Real-Time Bidding Platform**: Developed a logistics-focused RESTful API, reducing latency **by 60%** on the real-time bidding platform.

Software Developer

January 2021 - March 2022

Chengdu Juxinjuyi PYT LTD, China

- **Backend Development:** Utilized Django for efficient database management, authentication, and data handling. **Improved** backend processing speed **by 30%**.
- **App Design**: Designed features for property viewing and manager appointment scheduling, resulting in a **20% increase in user engagement**.
- PostgreSQL Integration: Integrated PostgreSQL for enhanced data storage and retrieval, improving overall system performance by 25%.
- Security Measures: Applied Django's security features, reducing potential security vulnerabilities by 50% for sensitive real estate data.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Machine-Learning Based TCP Security Action Prediction

Sep 2019 - Oct 2020

- Published a paper 'Machine-Learning Based TCP Security Action Prediction' on ICMCCE 2020, and be submitted to IEEE Xplore, El, Scopus for indexing.
- Implemented various machine learning models, including neural networks, SVM, AdaBoost, and logistic regression.

Kaggle - Google - Fast or Slow? Predict Al Model Runtime

Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

- **Secured a silver medal** in a Kaggle competition, ranking in the top 30 out of 600+ submitted parameter groups.
- Utilized a Graph Convolutional Network (GCN) model, incorporating coded node_opcod and node_config_feat for potential representations.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology University of New South Wales Bachelor of Management Chengdu University September 2021 - September 2023

September 2016 - June 2020